[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
[panting]
[screaming]
[gasps]
[panting]
BAFFLING TURN x OF x EVENTS
Oh, good. You're awake.
Where am I?
In a waiting room
that is next to the arena
for the Final Phase.
All righty, then.
[Gon] Oh, right.
I was in the middle of the Hunter Exam.
Your arm will be fine, by the way.
The break was clean and easily set.
In fact, that limb will be even stronger
once it mends.
In any case,
congratulations on your win, Gon.
-Mr. Satotz, I--
-You can't.
Just as someone
who has failed the Hunter Exam
can no longer pass,
someone who has passed the Hunter Exam
can no longer fail.
What you make of it is entirely up to you.
If you feel you're unqualified
to be a professional,
you may put away your license.
Or destroy it, if you wish.
You can even sell it,
though it's of no practical use
to anyone else.
However, you have officially passed
the Hunter Exam,
and no one who passes it
will ever be allowed to retake it.
Due to the efforts of our predecessors,
professional Hunters
are treated quite well.
As a result,
there is no end of applicants
seeking a license
for the worst intentions.
If it weren't for the likes of them,
we would gladly pass everyone who applies,
without exception.
Most professional Hunters value this card
even above their own lives.
All the same,
it's really nothing more
than a silly piece of junk.
What's important
is not the way that you become a Hunter,
but what you do.
What I do, huh?
[Satotz] Gon.
You must decide for yourself
when you're ready to use this card.
I'm confident
that you'll make the right choice.
You know,
I got a lot of help to get this far,
and I owe a lot of people
a bunch of favors.
Once I've paid everyone back,
then I think I'll be ready.
Then please allow me the honor
of congratulating you once again.
Thank you, Mr. Satotz.
What happened to the other applicants?
The Exam's still going on, right?
Oh, no. The Exam has already ended.
-Seriously?
-That's right.
You've been out for almost the entire day.
[gasps] The entire day?
The others who passed
are completing a brief orientation,
the same orientation you'll undergo later.
Who wound up failing?
It was...
Killua.
[gasps]
Killua failed?
But why?
I feel I should begin
by telling you about all that transpired
after you lost consciousness.
Perhaps that way,
you'll better understand the outcome.
Just as soon as you were out cold…
Whenever he wakes up,
he'll probably decline his advancement.
He's right.
Sounds like something Gon would do.
Only one person fails this round, right?
So, if Gon is disqualified,
then wouldn't that render
the rest of our upcoming fights
completely meaningless?
You've no need to worry.
Gon has certainly passed.
Nothing he says or does
can change that now.
[both sigh]
[Netero] As a matter of fact,
he could even throw a fit
and kill me where I stand,
but we still wouldn't be able
to revoke his license.
Yes, I see.
So why?
Why'd you let him win?
What did you say?
You didn't have to kill him.
With your skills,
you could've made him surrender...
somehow.
I expect, when I torture someone,
my victim will despise me
for the rest of their life.
It's more effective and less stressful.
When you're in pain,
your eyes show a gleam of hostility
toward the person responsible.
Even with the most extensive
training and discipline,
that sign of rage
is difficult to suppress.
But Gon's eyes had no such gleam.
Can you believe that?
I had just broken his arm.
But I could tell
just by looking into his eyes
that he had already forgotten
all about it.
So I guess you could say
the little guy won me over.
Hmm.
If you need a reason why I "let him win,"
there you have it.
[Satotz] You won over your opponent, Gon.
Hanzo admitted as much himself.
After that,
the second match of the Phase began.
[Masta] Round two! Kurapika versus Hisoka.
Begin!
[Satotz] After the two of them
had been fighting for a while…
[grunts]
[gasps]
[Hisoka chuckles]
[Hisoka] I lose this one.
[Satotz] And that's how Kurapika won.
[Gon] What did Hisoka say?
[Satotz] I couldn't say.
But I do know
that he conceded voluntarily.
The third match
pitted Hanzo against Pokkle.
Pokkle found himself
In much the same position as you,
but he admitted defeat.
Almost immediately, in fact.
I'm sorry, but I won't go easy on you.
[Satotz]
And with that, the match was over.
The fourth match was between
Hisoka and Bodoro.
[Bodoro yells]
[grunting]
[groans]
[Satotz]
The match was extremely one-sided,
but Bodoro flatly refused to give in.
[groaning]
[Satotz] However,
while Bodoro was lying on the floor,
Hisoka whispered something in his ear.
And this time, it was Bodoro
who surrendered.
The fifth match featured
Killua and Pokkle,
but Killua walked away
as soon as it began.
-[Pokkle] Huh?
-[Masta gasps]
In a confident tone, he declared…
Yeah, sorry.
But I'm just not interested
in fighting you.
[Satotz] He must have felt certain
he could win his next match.
But then,
Leorio requested
that the sixth match be postponed
while Bodoro recovered from his injuries.
So, in the meantime,
the match between Killua and Gitarrackur
was held.
[Masta] Begin!
[Satotz] It became apparent that Killua
had made a grave miscalculation.
It's been a while, Kil.
[gasps]
Big brother!
HUNTER GLOSSARY
ILLUMI
Wait. So Gitarrackur
is Killua's brother?
Yes.
And his name is Illumi.
[heavy breathing]
Hey.
He's Killua's brother?
Those needles were used
to change his appearance?
I heard you stabbed Mom and Milluki.
Guess so.
Mom couldn't stop crying.
Well, who would blame her?
Anybody'd cry if their kid did that.
She was just so happy.
[Leorio gasps]
[Illumi] She was delighted to see
that her son had finally grown up.
But she's concerned about you
being out on your own.
And she asked me to check up on you
when I got the chance.
Lucky me, huh?
I had absolutely no idea
that you wanted to be a Hunter.
As for me, I'm here to get a license
for a job that's coming up.
I don't actually want to become a Hunter.
I just felt like taking the Exam.
I see...
Well, that's a relief.
In that case, I have some advice for you.
You're not cut out to be a Hunter.
You were born for one purpose:
To be an assassin.
That's really what he said?
Killua mentioned his family,
but they sound crazy.
But that wasn't the extent of it.
You're a puppet of darkness,
devoid of passion.
There is nothing you desire,
nor is there anything you wish for.
As one who lives in the shadows,
the only pleasure you're capable of
is derived from causing death.
Because that's how Dad and I raised you.
What do you imagine
that you would accomplish
by becoming a Hunter?
[Killua] It's true.
I don't really want to be a Hunter.
But...
everyone wants something.
Even me.
-[Illumi] You don't.
-Wrong!
There is something that I really want!
[Illumi] Hmm...
Enlighten me. What is it that you want?
Hmm...
What's the matter?
There really isn't anything, is there?
There is!
I...
want to be...
friends with Gon.
I'm... I'm just so sick of killing people.
I want to be friends with Gon...
and just have fun.
Impossible.
You are incapable of friendship.
The only thing that you can do
is discern whether or not
you can kill them.
That is all you were ever taught.
Gon is such a radiant personality
that you don't know how to classify him.
You don't actually desire his friendship.
No…
[Illumi] If you stay with him,
one day you'll end up
wanting to kill him.
You'll wonder if you can.
And you'll want to find out.
Because…
you are, by nature, a murderer.
[shuddering breaths]
[grumbles]
We've warned you already, sir.
-So please…
-[Leorio] Yeah, yeah, I know.
[shouting] Killua!
I couldn't care less
if this guy's your brother, all right?
He's a worthless piece of crap!
So don't listen to him!
Just beat the crap out of him like usual
and win!
You want to become friends with Gon?
Are you kiddin' me?
You're already friends!
How do you not know that?
-[Killua gasps]
-[Illumi] Huh?
[Leorio]
Gon sure seems to think so, anyway!
Is that true?
Hell yeah, it's true, you idiot!
Oh, no. That isn't good.
So he already considers Kil a friend?
Fine. Then I'll just kill Gon!
[all gasp]
[Illumi]
Assassins have no use for friends.
They only get in the way.
[shuddering breaths]
Where can I find him?
[examiner] Please, wait a second!
The match is still--
[groans]
[painful gurgling]
-[Illumi] Where?
-[examiner groans]
[strained]
He's in the waiting room right over there…
-[Illumi] Thank you.
-[groaning in pain]
Hmm?
Oh, what a pain.
I need to acquire a Hunter's license
right now
so I can do my job.
But if I kill them, I'll fail,
and then Kil will pass automatically.
Oh, no!
The same thing will happen
if I kill Gon.
Hmm... Wait!
[chuckling]
I'll pass the Exam and then kill Gon!
[shuddering breaths]
You bastard!
[Illumi] If I pass the Exam first,
I can kill everyone here
and still keep my license,
isn't that right?
Well... yes, according to the rulebook.
[Illumi] Did you hear that, Kil?
If you really want to save Gon,
you're going to have to beat me.
Will you fight me to save your friend?
You can't do it, can you?
Because deep down,
you're more worried about whether
you can defeat me than anything else,
aren't you?
[gasps]
[Illumi]
And... you already know the answer.
"I'm not strong enough
to beat my big brother."
Remember the lesson I drilled into you?
Never go up against a superior opponent.
[panicked breathing]
[Illumi] Don't move!
Move one more inch,
and I'll assume the fight has begun.
The same goes for if our bodies
come in contact with each other.
The fight starts.
There is only one way to stop me,
and you know it.
But don't forget...
If you decide that you won't fight me,
your dear Gon will certainly die.
Take him out, Killua!
We'll protect you!
He won't kill you or Gon!
We'll do whatever we have to do
to stop him!
Go on! Let him have it!
[shuddering breath]
[Killua] You win, Illumi.
I admit defeat.
[Kurapika and Leorio gasping]
Oh! Excellent!
No need for us to fight then, huh?
[laughs]
I lied, Kil.
I was never going to kill Gon.
That was only a test
to see what you were made of.
And now I know for certain.
You are simply not qualified
to make friends.
Not that you need any.
You'll keep doing what you've always done:
the job Dad and I trained you to do.
I'll order you to take the Hunter Exam
when the time is right.
But not now.
[Satotz]
Something drained out of Killua then.
Leorio and Kurapika
did their best to help,
but he simply wouldn't respond.
The sixth match
was between Leorio and Bodoro.
Bodoro had recovered,
but at the onset of the match…
[Masta] Begin!
[Satotz] It was over in a flash.
And so, just like that,
Killua killed Bodoro.
The committee disqualified him,
though that goes without saying.
-[Satotz] Gon!
-[Gon] Where is everybody?
[Satotz] You must lie down!
You need to rest!
[footsteps approaching]
Gon!
Apologize to Killua!
[narrator] Gon was angry.
Illumi had trampled on Killua's desire
to be Gon's friend,
sending his younger brother
into deep despair.
In fact, Gon was more than angry.
He was furious.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time: Some Brother Trouble!
Do Leorio and I look alike?
Get outta here…